# M A G D A L E N A S A D L O

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



### EXPERTISE



SOFTWARE ENGINEERING
FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT
TEST DRIVEN DEVELOPMENT
BANKING

# TECH SKILLS



#### **PROGRAMING**

Java SEE, Java EE, Hibernate, Spring

### WEB TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, AngularJS, REST, HTML5, CSS

#### **DATABASES**

Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Firebase TOOLS

Git, Openshift, Docker, Jenkins, JIRA, Confluence

#### OPERATING SYSTEMS

Windows NT, UNIX, Mac OS

#### **DEVELOPMENT**

Agile (Scrum), TDD, Conitinuous Integratiom, Clean Code, Design Patterns



### PROFILE

I am a software engineer with over seven years of experience in development of Java EE applications. I am curious, communicative and open to change. My objective is to participate in challenging projects, where I am able to apply best practices of software development in order to deliver reliable, maintainable and secure software.



### EXPERIENCE

# **Contractig in financial sector**, Zurich, Switzerland Fullstack software engineer/Consultant

FEBRUARY 2018 - JUNE 2019

Various positions in the banking sector in Zurich (ZKB, Julius Bär, Vontobel):

- Improvements for the online banking platform (Java EE/JSP/Angular)
- New features for an internal tool for client advisors (TypeScript/AngularJS)
- Backend development including database design, testing, continuous integration and delivery, performance monitoring (Java EE/JBoss/Hibernate/REST/JMS/JBoss/Oracle DB) of an internal tool for task management
- Proof of concept for migration of existing microservices to containerized infrastructure using Openshift/Docker
- Improvements/extension to existing services facilitating JMS communication between different parts of the platform landscape

### Zuhlke Engineering, Schlieren, Zurich Area, Switzerland

Software enigineer/Consultant

APRIL 2016 - FEBRUARY 2018

Software engineering consultant for companies from the financial sector. Design, frontend and backend web development, testing, code reviews, guidance in application of agile methodologies (Scrum).

#### **PROJECTS**

**Julius Bär** – backend development for an internal web application for task workflow management for relationship managers.

SIX – frontend web development (TypeScript/Angular) and microservices infrastructure setup (Openshift/Docker) for the new TPA platform

### Swissquote, Gland, Geneva Area, Switzerland

Software enigineer

MARCH 2014 - FEBRUARY 2016

Full-stack development and maintenance of an ePrivate Banking - Java-based roboadvisor platform. Technical lead for one of the offshore teams.



## EDUCATION

#### AGH University of Science and Technology, Kraków, Poland

Technical physics major with specialization in computational physics.

 $\underline{\mathsf{MASTER}\ \mathsf{THESIS}}\ (\mathsf{written}\ \mathsf{in}\ \mathsf{English}) \text{: ``Multiband mixing for valence band holes in semiconductor nanostructures of various dimensionalities''}\ (\mathsf{Matlab})$ 

<u>BACHELOR THESIS</u>: "Visualization of metallic complexes using OpenGL library" (C++, OpenGL)

#### Stockholm University, Stockholm, Sweden

Erasmus student exchange



# MAGDALENA SADLO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



### LANGUAGES



ENGLISH

Full professional proficiency

GERMAN

Professional working proficiency

FRENCH

Limited working proficiency

<u>POLISH</u>

Mother tongue

<u>SWEDISH</u>

Elementary proficiency

### SOCIAL SKILLS



OPEN

COMMUNICATIVE

TEAM PLAYER

### INTERESTS









HIKING SNOWBOARD TRAVELING YOGA



### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Motorola Solutions, Krakow, Poland

Software engineer

OCTOBER 2012 - FEBRUARY 2014

Development, maintenance and preparation of new releases of software for the authentication of radios in the infrastructure (Java based application with Swing GUI), participation in system testing both on the product level as well as the system integration tests.

#### Ikonoskop, Stockholm, Sweden Trainee

MARCH 2012 - APRIL 2012

Development of an Android application that allowed remote control of a professional film camera via USB cable. The purpose of the application was to provide a user-friendly interface to be an alternative to the complicated and unintuitive buttons on the camera.

#### Universidade Federal de Ouro Preto, João Monlevade, Minas Gerais, Brazil Trainee

AUGUST 2010 - SEPTEMBER 2010

Analysis of vibrations from broken and healthy steel sleepers using neural networks (Matlab) in order to find a way to distinguish one from the other.



# CERTIFICATES

Professional Scrum Master I

Professional Scrum Developer I

Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 6 Programmer

Certificate in Advanced English C1

German Goethe-Zertifikat B2

French DELF B2



# MY INSPIRATION

<u>Shoshana Zuboff</u> "The Age of Surveillance Capitalism"

<u>Robert C. Martin</u> "Clean Code: A handbook of agile software craftsmanship"

<u>Andrew Hunt</u> "The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master"

